Career Objective

12+ year of front-end web developer experience working with diverse clients and projects, showcasing my strong development and leadership skills. I have expert-level knowledge of W3C standards, cross-browser/platform development, accessibility, and a solid understanding of the principles of information architecture. I have the ability to quickly hand-code clean HTML/CSS from Photoshop/Sketch/Zeplin mock-ups, functional specs and use cases, with understanding of interaction design and user-centered design methods and practices. I have experience in refactoring existing codebase and in understanding existing implementations to decide to refactor or rewrite. I enjoy working in Agile development and am extremely comfortable with SCRUM process.

Skills and Competencies

Dev HTML5 (jade), CSS (LESS, SASS), XML/XSLT, JSON, YAML, Twig

JavaScript: jQuery, Dojo, AJAX, Node, Grunt, Gulp, Bower, Bootstrap, Angular, Backbone, Handlebars, React, vue.js Coding Environment/CMS: PHP, SQL, WordPress, Craft CMS, Squarespace, Hybris, Adobe CQ/AEM, Squarespace

Tools Project Management/Bug Tracking: Jira, Sharepoint, Google Suite, Trello, SiteLife, BugZilla, Redmine

Versioning: Tortoise SVN, VCS, Versions, GitHub, VisualSVN, BitBucket

Links LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/dessin GitHub: https://github.com/MsDacia

Personal: http://msdacia.com/portfolio.php

Work Experience

Senior Presentation Layer Developer, 05/2016 to 02/2017

Razorfish Commerce, Remote

- Creating of all coded presentation layer deliverables utilizing HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, Backbone, SASS, JSON within Adobe AEM/CQ and Hybris
- Converting HTML pages from Sketch/Zeplin to microsites and landing pages for clients
- Working within agile, SCRUM-based environment on large commerce accounts
- Architecting client sites using Grunt/Gulp, setting up project framework and developing single-page applications using AWS

Senior Front-End Web Developer (Independent Contractor), 05/2016 to 11/2016 Super Humane, Remote

- Developed templates, including responsive web design using SASS and HTML, JSON/Twig within JSX React templates from Invision and Sketch mockups
- Designed JSON API within Craft CMS
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings, sprint planning meetings, and retrospective via Google Hangouts

Senior Front-End Web Developer (Freelance), 03/2015 to 07/2016

Chicago, Illinois

- Developed HTML5/CSS3 front-end templates, sites and applications, including responsive web design using technologies including but not limited to CSS, HTML, AJAX, JavaScript (jquery, dojo, Bootstrap, Backbone.JS and Angular.js), XML/XSLT, API, and JSON, while working efficiently with a strong attention to detail and accuracy
- Designed and maintained a variety of single and multi-page websites for clients, including Hyatt Special Event (Adobe CQ), Intel POS (multi-platform), McDonalds, Allstate Veterans (<u>allstateveterans.com</u>), Cavalry (Squarespace https://cavalry.squarespace.com/), Czarnowski (WordPress czarnowski.com), Resq (WordPress resqbiz.com), Advocate (WordPress advocate.io)

Senior Front-End Web Developer, 12/2013 to 06/2015

Peapod, Chicago, Illinois

- Produced HTML5/CSS page templates from master source documents for desktop and mobile web applications using technologies including CSS3, HTML, AJAX, JavaScript, backbone.js, XML/XSLT, JSP, API, JSON, and ATG CMS
- Developed front-end sites and applications, including responsive web design, vanilla JavaScript, RESTful API integration, and rich media production and social media integration while working efficiently with a strong attention to detail and accuracy
- Created and maintained the UI toolkit and other internal projects in ATG Business Control Center, the internal CMS
- Developed in agile development environment, including scrums, backlog grooming, sprint development timelines
- Handled the deployment process for the end of sprint code release to production, along with documentation of our process

Senior Front-End Web Developer, 06/2008 to 12/2013

Acquity Group, Chicago, Illinois

- Expertise in producing HTML5/CSS page templates from master source documents for desktop and mobile web
 applications using technologies including but not limited to CSS, HTML, AJAX, JavaScript, XML/XSLT, JSP, PHP, API,
 JSON, and CMS' such as Adobe CQ and Hybris
- Expertise coaching front-end developers in standards, compliant methodologies, repeatable processes, cross browser, and cross platform website and application development, including building out our formal QA process
- Architected and developed front-end sites and applications, including responsive web design, JavaScript (both jQuery and dojo frameworks), RESTful API integration, and rich media production and social media integration while working efficiently with a strong attention to detail and accuracy
- Provided appropriate guidance and oversight to team members to ensure quality of deliverables, mentoring college hires
- Provided estimates on project deliverables based on level of effort, resources, and requirements

Web Developer (Independent Contractor), 02/2004 to 12/2011

Chicago, Illinois

- Hand-coded semantic websites using HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript with jQuery, AJAX, PHP, MySQL, XML/ XSLT
- Created symptom checker tool for American Academy of Pediatrics
 (http://www.healthychildren.org/english/tips-tools/symptom-checker/Pages/default.aspx) using XHTML/CSS3 and jQuery as a short-term contractor
- Modified and reformating templates for 60+ online news publications, including Suntimes.com, using XHTML/CSS3 and JavaScript with jQuery framework as a short-term contractor while working with third-party affiliates in implementing Sun-Times Media templates, including troubleshooting and modified page structure
- Provided both front- and back-end web development using XHTML/CSS3, PHP, and JavaScript, as well as, bug-fixing and QA testing for PizzaHut.com redesign with primary focus on IE6 with Quik Order as a short-term contractor
- Hand-coded pixel-perfect site for client, Saatchi & Saatchi (<u>ILOVENY.com</u>) using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX
- Contracted with Chicago Booth School of Business in both front- and back-end web development by hand-coded semantic web pages and microsites in an agile environment using XHTML/CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, XML/ XSLT, along with RSS and Web Service integration, integrated web services, API, and Google Mash-ups
- Executed cross-browser QA testing/debugging along with web standards and ensuring accessibility and W3C compliance
- Produced web assets, by slicing and editing images in Photoshop and page layout
- Utilized experience and judgment to plan around milestone schedules in order to manage multiple deadline driven projects
- Monitored status and progress of websites with Google Analytics and fixed server- and client-side errors generated
- Tested website for functionality for cross-browser and cross-platform issues and enforced coding W3C standards

Education

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, Illinois, 08/1997 to 05/2002

Major: Professional and Technical Communications, Bachelor of Science Degree Minor: Management

Specialization: CAD & Graphics Design for Non-Engineers